Based in: London, NW10 7GL, UK

# Marius OLARIU

marius.lucian.olariu @gmail.com linkedin.com/in/mlo1994

### **Summary**

I am a degree educated Software Engineer with 3 years of experience in developing software for Web and Desktop Operating Systems. The best professional quality that I have is the love for learning and my most important skills are: Java, Spring, JavaScript and React.

### **Employment**

Sofware Engineer Diffblue Aug 2020 - present

In this role, I am writing software in Java in an Agile environment for Diffblue Cover, a tool powered by AI that automatically generates (unit) tests for Java code. I make a consistent commitment to growth by embracing continuous learning (i.e. each Sprint I study a topic relevant for my work) and by taking new responsibilities (e.g. lead stand-ups and Sprint Retrospectives). Last, but not least, I set up and maintain an online environment where the product can be tried, see diffblue.com/try-cover-browser.

Technologies used: Java, Spring, JUnit, Maven, Git

### **Junior Full Stack Engineer**

#### **New Verve Consulting**

Aug 2019 - Aug 2020

Played an important role in the development and launch of a cloud add-on for Jira. The add-on allows you to bring context to Jira tickets by linking them to customer data. I helped through pair-programming sessions one of my colleagues to transition from a Technical Consultant position to a Developer one. Managed my time between writing my MSc dissertation and the position successfully.

Technologies used: JavaScript, React, Node, Jest, Git

#### **Junior Software Engineer**

### SSI Schaefer Romania

Sept. 2017 - Aug 2018

Got exposed to the world of professional software development with Java as well as finishing my last year of BSc studies in Computer Science. I worked on the development of software for a vertical lift module (LOGIMAT) that allowed goods in a warehouse to be stored and managed efficiently. Managed my time successfully between the position and my last year of BSc studies.

Technologies used: Java, SQL, JUnit, HQL, Git

### **Education**

### Paisley, Scotland

## West University Scotland

Sept 2018 - Feb 2020

- Received an MSc degree with distinction in "Mobile Web Development"
- MSc thesis: Development and Evalutaion of the User Experience of a Mobile Booking Application
- Courses: Web Development, Mobile Networks and Smartphone Apps, Human-Computer Interaction etc.

#### Timisoara, Romania

#### **Polytechnic University**

Sept 2014 - June 2018

- Received a Bachelor degree with distinction in "Computer and Software Engineering"
- BSc project: HelpMeSee Navigation assistant for visually impaired people
- Courses: Computer Programming, Algorithms, Operating Systems, Databases etc.

#### Nijmegen, The Netherlands

#### **Radboud University**

Feb 2017 - Jul 2017

• exchange semester through Erasmus programme

#### Linköping, Sweden

### **Linköping University**

Sept 2016 - Jan 2017

• exchange semester through Erasmus programme

#### **Technical Experience**

### **Personal Projects**

• Plus One Mentor App (2019) - Mobile and Web solution for the youth work of YMCA Paisley and also used for my MSc research. This mobile solution allows YMCA volunteers to schedule appointments with mentees

and also to provide feedback on them. The Web solution allows the manager to see an activity overview for each YMCA volunteer within his organization. Java API Android, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Firebase Solutions, Git

- HelpMeSee (2018) Navigation assistant for visually impaired people, namely an Android application through
  which the visually impaired user can set a certain destination and will receive real-time voice instruction on
  how to get to it. Demo video, code and documentation can be found on my GitHub account. Java API Android,
  MVC architecture, LaTeX documentation, git
- WordWar (2017) Android multiplayer game for language learning. The game looks similar to a Trivia game, namely, the players compete to conquer tiles of the map by remembering the word translation. Java LibGDX
- RoboApp (2016) Android app working as a remote control for a robo-car. The app was developed during a student competition organized by Continental Automotive Romania, "inGENIUOSLY". The aim of the competition was to build an "autonomous" robo-car that had to get out of a maze city by detecting traffic signs as fast as possible. Java API Android

### **Additional Experience and Awards**

- **SFC Scholarship** (2018). A scholarship awarded by the Scottish Funding Council (SFC) that covered the tuition fee for my master degree programme.
- Third Prize, inGENIOUSly (2016). My team received this prize at the "inGENIOUSly" competition organized by Continental Automotive Romania.

### **Volunteering**

# Paisley, Scotland YMCA Paisley Sept 2018 - Aug 2019

- I went to a coding club where I help young people (8-18 years old) to learn programming.
- More info: http://www.paisleyymca.org/

#### **Online**

- GitHub: https://github.com/mariusolariu
- Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/mlo1994

### **Soft Skills**

- I consider myself: optimistic, self-motivated, team-player and friendly.
- languages: Romanian (native), English (upper-intermediate)
- driving licence (2012)